Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Information Technology]



Software Engineer seeking roles in Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Application Analyst, Solution Architect, Azure, AWS, HTML, XML, MS Access, Linux, DevOps, SQL, SOAP UI, Testing and Maintenance, Project Management, Data Collection and analysis



Current Designation: Software Engineer

Current Company: Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd

Current Location: Gurgaon

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, Application Analyst, Solution Architect, Azure, AWS, HTML, XML, MS

Access, Linux, DevOps, SQL, SOAP UI, Testing and Maintenance, Project Management, Data Collection and

analysis, Pricing Analysis, Pricing, CI, Cd

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Software Engineer with over 3 years of successfull experience. Recognized consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success in IT industry. Enthusiastic and eager to contribute to team success through smart work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Clear understanding of task and completed training in AWS Solution Architect. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in AWS now and holds mastering knowledge with AWS and Azure. Proven success in leadership, operational excellence and organizational development with keen understanding of elements. True team player with strengths in adaptability and accuracy. Quickly learn and master new technologies and working in both team and self-directed settings.

Work Experience

Virtusa Consulting Services Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer Mar 2018 to Till Date

Understands the requirement and based upon that do the certain analysis which includes tracking the stack trace of transaction either through the glowroot or through server, work upon the data which includes SQL query, Manual testing when the deployment is done, we also work on the API because through API different interfaces interact in the designed system and SOAP UI is used to hit the web service call, From the admin part Docker image gets formed at the Jenkins and that Image is used in Rancher while deployment, Stack trace analysis and working on the analysis, day-to-day interactions with the international clients, Requirement gathering from the client and work upon the requirement in the stipulated time-stamp, fetching and updating the Idap data, Linux is used while uploading file to server or running script.

Virtusa Polaris as Software Engineer Mar 2018 to Mar 2018

=>Understand the customer (internal, external) requirements and produce quotes for different type of technologies like(WAVE, Ethernet, ULL FTTH, xDSL, Leased lines, GCR).

=>Price upload so that end customer can see the correct

price with the offer applied. Troubleshoting customer issue if any is raised.

=>Tested troubleshooting methods, devised

innovative solutions, and documented resolutions for inclusion in

knowledge for team.

=>Maintained effective customer relationships and

identified future business opportunities to support and strengthen corporate

=>Worked closely with software development and

testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.

=>Discussed project progress with customers, collected

feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.

=>Improved system performance by making proactive

adjustments and resolving bugs.

Persistent Systems as Associate Software Engineer Mar 2017 to Feb 2018

=>Debugged code and located root causes of problems by reviewing configuration files and logs. =>Implemented process management system using Java language.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Information Technology) from Trident Academy of Creative Technology, Bhuvaneshwar in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used	Experience
HTML and XML		2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SOAP UI, SQL Query		2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
MS ACCESS		2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Linux		1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
CI	0	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Expert			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General

Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No

Employment Status: Full time